Guide to the Parliamentary Extracrs, Lists, Etc.
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Parliamentary extracts, lists, etc.]
1501-1700
OSBORN FB160
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.17
(1 volume)
Collection, in multiple hands, of eight booklets bound into one volume, primarily on Parliamentary activities. The manuscript begins with a list of the members of Parliament between 1295 and 1327. Other items include extracts from Parliamentary journals; a list of the customs and privileges of both Houses of Parliament by Robert Bowyer; rules for the House of Commons; and, in Browne's hand, a patent transferring Humphrey de Bohun, Earl of Hereford's office of Constable of England to his brother, dated 1338.
Browne, John, approximately 1608-1691
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb160. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Magna carta; Legal documents; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1066-1485; Great Britain -- Religious life and customs -- 17th century; Commonplace books; Bowyer, Robert, -1622; Browne, John, approximately 1608-1691; Hereford, Humphrey de Bohun, Earl of, 1309-1361; Northampton, William de Bohun, Earl of, d.1360; Great Britain. Parliament; Braye, Alfred Verney-Cave, Baron, 1849-1928 -- Bookplate
- Osborn fb160
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT, 1295-1327. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - [Lists of the members 1295-1327, 17th century], [n.d.] (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      36 p.
      Anonymous MS.
      f.1.
  - BOWYER, ROBERT, D.1621
    - [Extracts from the records and journals of Parliament, 1307-1601, c. early 17th century] (Box 1)
      218 p.
      MS with blank pages, some damage.
      Divided in four separate parts, bound
      in the following order: Parliaments 4
      Edw.III - 22 Edw.IV; Parliaments Edw.
      VI - Philip & Mary; Parliaments of
      Henry VIII; Parliaments of Elizabeth
      I. The early extracts are dates of
      summons. Includes Bowyer's comments
      on lost records, etc.
      f.2.
  - BOWYER, ROBERT, D.1621
    - "Customes and priviledges of the neither house of parliament" (Box 1)
      [17th century]
      22 p.
      MS. Title in the hand of John Browne.
      Some blank pages. Extracts from the
      journals of Elizabethan Parliaments
      (1571-1586).
      f.3.
  - HEREFORD, HUMPHREY DE BOHUN, EARL OF, 1309-1361
    - [Patent whereby author transfers his office of Constable of England to his brother on 12 June 1338, 17th century] (Box 1)
      2 p.
      MS copy in the hand of John Browne.
      William de Bohun, earl of Northampton
      (d.1360). In Latin.
      f.4.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Extracts and notes on the history of the Magna Carta, 17th century] (Box 1)
      3 p.
      Autograph MS in Latin.
      Includes marginal references and
      notes.
      f.5.
  - BROWNE, JOHN, D.1691.
    - [Extracts and notes concerning the hierarchy of the Church, 17th century] (Box 1)
      MS in Latin & English. Includes
      citations from Bishop Jewell.
      Doctrinal and controversial works.
      f.6.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT. HOUSE OF LORDS.
    - "Remembrances of Order and decencie to be kepte in the upper House of Parliament..." (Box 1)
      18 p.
      MS in the hand of John Browne.
      Procedure, rules for proxies, etc.
      f.7.
  - GREAT BRITAIN. PARLIAMENT. HOUSE OF COMMONS.
    - "Rules and Orders of the House of Commons" (Box 1)
      [late 16th century]
      33 p.
      Anonymous MS. Includes a table of
      contents divided into topics such as
      choice of speaker, reading of bills,
      general pardon, etc.
      f.8.